Vishal Tank

Phone: (+91) 99090 15478

GitHub: github.com/vishaltank

Email: vishal.97t@gmail.com
Profile: vishaltank.github.io

ABOUT

A Web Developer and an enthusiastic coder, with working experience of around 1.5 years in web applications development along with various new technologies like IoT and Chat-bots. I have participated in multiple online competitive coding practices and have also developed many applications in multiple languages and technologies.

EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer, Kevit Technologies

Rajkot, Gujarat (Mar 2019 – June 2019)

The projects I worked on used Node.js as backend and MongoDB as database. My main contribution was in a project which was basically a Framework that lets a user create chat-bots as they need without having any technical knowledge.

- Learned JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, MongoDB and Microsoft Bot Framework.
- Third party API integrations in the project like Google and Facebook APIs.
- Learned how to deploy and maintain web applications on a server.
- Designed and developed backend solutions for multiple Live projects.
- Worked with frontend developers and collaborated often to solve issues occurring in the project.

Full Stack Developer, Volansys Technologies

Ahmedabad, Gujarat (Aug 2019 - Present)

My main project was a UI enabled cabin control system for cabin crew inside of an airplane. Basically, the goal is to help the airplane cabin crew easily manage passenger requests and manage all relevant announcements, communications etc. wirelessly using IoT technology.

- Learned Angular, React, AWS and IoT related technologies.
- Collaborated with Embedded and Android departments to design solutions of various problems.
- Designed and developed multiple Web + IoT related features in projects.
- Gaining experience in many aspects of web development like AWS, Nginx, Docker etc.

SKILLS

BACKEND

Node.js NoSQL (MongoDB) Unit/Integration Testing

FRONTEND

Angular React.js (Beginner)

LANGUAGES

JavaScript, TypeScript C, C++ Java

OTHER

Amazon Web Services (AWS) Algorithm & Data Structures IoT with Node & Angular

PROJECTS

Name: Pictionary (Work in-progress)

Platform: Node.js, Angular, TypeScript, MongoDB

Description: It's an online Pictionary game. People can create and join Rooms that has functionality of

real-time group chat and drawing, round wise turns, score keeping and much more.

Name: Node.ts (Work in-progress)

Platform: Node.js, TypeScript, MongoDB

Description: I started working on a bootstrapping library that creates your initial project structure and express application in TypeScript directly for you, just like some existing tools for example 'express-

generator', 'create-react-app'.

Name: NoteUp

Platform: Android, Java

Description: NoteUp is a simple note taking application, an is an easy way to keep track of your Important notes that you have to keep in your phone from where you can fetch it anytime and get reminded about

it in a simple way!

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science (2015-2019)

Government Engineering College, Rajkot

Percentage: 7.78 (CGPA)

H.S.C (2013-2015)

Shree P. V. Modi High School, Rajkot

Percentage: 72 %

S.S.C (2012-2013)

Shree P. V. Modi High School, Rajkot

Percentage: 81 %

HOBBIES

Gaming

Exploring New Technological Innovations